1
00:00:06,190 --> 00:00:12,170
<font color=#70DBDB>=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=http://ytet.org=-   proudly presents </font>

2
00:01:35,040 --> 00:01:43,160
<font color=#70DBDB>-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- 时间轴调校:紫月

3
00:01:43,300 --> 00:01:47,660
<font color=#70DBDB>Game of thrones season04 ep09</font>

4
00:02:24,680 --> 00:02:26,030
What was she like?

5
00:02:29,350 --> 00:02:30,270
She...

6
00:02:33,110 --> 00:02:35,080
she had red hair.

7
00:02:37,190 --> 00:02:38,150
Oh?

8
00:02:39,280 --> 00:02:41,700
- How big were her feet? 
- What do you want me to say?

9
00:02:41,750 --> 00:02:45,080
I want you to tell me what it was like to have someone.

10
00:02:45,120 --> 00:02:47,090
To be with someone.

11
00:02:47,120 --> 00:02:49,480
To love someone and have them love you back.

12
00:02:53,010 --> 00:02:56,350
We're all gonna die a lot sooner than I'd planned.

13
00:02:57,380 --> 00:03:00,020
You're the closest I'll ever get to knowing.

14
00:03:03,550 --> 00:03:05,040
So you and Gilly never?

15
00:03:05,190 --> 00:03:06,070
No.

16
00:03:06,520 --> 00:03:08,010
She just had a baby.

17
00:03:11,530 --> 00:03:12,680
And she never offered.

18
00:03:13,030 --> 00:03:14,480
But if she had,

19
00:03:15,980 --> 00:03:16,950
you would have?

20
00:03:18,200 --> 00:03:20,790
You'd have broken your vows?

21
00:03:24,910 --> 00:03:26,990
The interesting thing is,

22
00:03:27,000 --> 00:03:30,080
our vows never specifically forbid

23
00:03:30,130 --> 00:03:32,130
intimate relations with women.

24
00:03:32,170 --> 00:03:33,100
What?

25
00:03:33,830 --> 00:03:37,250
"I shall take no wife," yes,that's in there. There's no denying that.

26
00:03:37,300 --> 00:03:39,720
"I shall father no children." It's very specific.

27
00:03:39,760 --> 00:03:42,510
But what do our vows have to say about other...

28
00:03:42,560 --> 00:03:45,730
activities is open to interpretation.

29
00:03:47,680 --> 00:03:51,180
I don't think Ser Alliser cares much for interpretation.

30
00:03:55,520 --> 00:03:58,690
Anyway,there's nothing for him to interpret.

31
00:03:58,690 --> 00:04:00,690
We didn't.

32
00:04:04,110 --> 00:04:06,080
So what's it like?

33
00:04:07,830 --> 00:04:09,670
It's...

34
00:04:10,950 --> 00:04:14,710
there's this person, this whole other person.

35
00:04:14,710 --> 00:04:18,130
And you're wrapped up in them and they're wrapped up in you.

36
00:04:18,180 --> 00:04:20,350
And you--

37
00:04:20,380 --> 00:04:22,380
for a little--

38
00:04:22,380 --> 00:04:24,720
for a little while, you're more than just you.

39
00:04:24,720 --> 00:04:28,020
You're-- I don't know. I'm not a bleeding poet.

40
00:04:28,060 --> 00:04:29,940
No,you're really not.

41
00:04:29,970 --> 00:04:31,860
What did I get for it?

42
00:04:31,890 --> 00:04:34,810
An arrow six inches from my heart.

43
00:04:36,310 --> 00:04:38,900
There'll be arrows for all of us soon,I imagine.

44
00:04:38,950 --> 00:04:40,570
There will.

45
00:04:40,570 --> 00:04:43,930
They've already done the worst thing to me they could ever do.

46
00:04:46,740 --> 00:04:48,740
Go get some sleep,Sam.

47
00:04:48,790 --> 00:04:51,040
I'll take this watch.

48
00:05:33,620 --> 00:05:36,670
Did I ever tell you about her?

49
00:05:36,710 --> 00:05:39,790
- My Sheila? - Yes.

50
00:05:39,790 --> 00:05:42,130
That was a night to remember.

51
00:05:42,180 --> 00:05:45,630
Of course,I'd had a good bit to drink.

52
00:05:47,380 --> 00:05:48,850
Her fangs were sharp,

53
00:05:48,890 --> 00:05:51,100
but she knew how to use them.

54
00:05:51,140 --> 00:05:54,890
And she was nice and soft down below.

55
00:05:54,940 --> 00:05:57,530
No,she was no ordinary beast.

56
00:05:57,560 --> 00:05:59,450
Many is the man who--

57
00:05:59,480 --> 00:06:01,560
I know you never fucked a bear.

58
00:06:01,620 --> 00:06:04,370
You know you never fucked a bear.

59
00:06:04,400 --> 00:06:07,650
Right now I don't want to think about the bear you never fucked.

60
00:06:07,700 --> 00:06:10,820
Right now all I want to think about

61
00:06:10,830 --> 00:06:13,630
is each one of these arrows finding its way into a crow's heart.

62
00:06:15,160 --> 00:06:17,210
We could be waiting here a while.

63
00:06:17,250 --> 00:06:18,580
Good.

64
00:06:18,630 --> 00:06:20,910
The longer we wait, the more arrows I'll have.

65
00:06:25,010 --> 00:06:28,220
They came up here to our land

66
00:06:28,260 --> 00:06:30,810
and put up a big wall and said it was theirs.

67
00:06:30,840 --> 00:06:33,230
Then they started hunting us down.

68
00:06:35,020 --> 00:06:38,570
This time,we're the ones doing the hunting.

69
00:06:40,270 --> 00:06:43,070
You've got a lot to say about killing.

70
00:06:43,110 --> 00:06:45,190
Even more words than arrows.

71
00:06:46,860 --> 00:06:49,700
Back in those villages,I killed just as many of them as you did.

72
00:06:49,750 --> 00:06:51,750
More,I reckon.

73
00:06:51,780 --> 00:06:55,870
Yes,but none of those were your crow lover.

74
00:06:55,870 --> 00:06:57,670
I probably killed him already.

75
00:06:57,700 --> 00:06:59,120
<i>So you've said.</i>

76
00:06:59,170 --> 00:07:01,340
And if not,

77
00:07:01,370 --> 00:07:05,040
the only thing left of him is gonna be his fun bits hanging around my neck.

78
00:07:05,050 --> 00:07:06,890
<i>More words.</i>

79
00:07:06,930 --> 00:07:09,270
Know what I think you do when you see him?

80
00:07:09,300 --> 00:07:13,140
Serve him up a nice juicy slice of ginger minge.

81
00:07:16,140 --> 00:07:19,530
You been thinking about that ginger minge?

82
00:07:21,140 --> 00:07:22,900
Wondering what I taste like?

83
00:07:25,830 --> 00:07:27,020
Maybe I have.

84
00:07:28,450 --> 00:07:30,650
Jon Snow is mine.

85
00:07:32,790 --> 00:07:34,910
Anyone else tries to kill him,

86
00:07:34,920 --> 00:07:37,080
I'll have an arrow for them.

87
00:07:40,130 --> 00:07:44,130
And not one of your bald friends is fast enough to stop me.

88
00:08:05,240 --> 00:08:10,120
And what is it that couldn't wait until morning,Tarly?

89
00:08:10,160 --> 00:08:11,290
Maester Aemon.

90
00:08:12,330 --> 00:08:14,830
- How did you know-- - That it was you?

91
00:08:14,880 --> 00:08:17,470
Who else but Samwell Tarly

92
00:08:17,500 --> 00:08:21,350
would be wasting candlesto read  in the middleof the night?

93
00:08:25,640 --> 00:08:28,080
- Let me help you. - Oh,no need.

94
00:08:29,480 --> 00:08:31,560
I know my way around this library

95
00:08:31,600 --> 00:08:34,180
better than any other place in Castle Black.

96
00:08:34,180 --> 00:08:36,520
Thousands of books

97
00:08:36,520 --> 00:08:38,850
and no eyes to read them.

98
00:08:38,860 --> 00:08:42,910
Old age is a wonderful source of ironies

99
00:08:42,940 --> 00:08:45,110
if nothing else.

100
00:08:45,160 --> 00:08:47,660
But you didn't answer my question.

101
00:08:47,700 --> 00:08:49,280
What are you reading?

102
00:08:49,330 --> 00:08:51,700
Maester Faull.

103
00:08:51,700 --> 00:08:54,700
Ah,the wildlings.

104
00:08:54,700 --> 00:08:58,290
I can assure you that the closest Maester Faull

105
00:08:58,340 --> 00:09:01,710
ever got to a wildling was this very library.

106
00:09:01,710 --> 00:09:04,680
But what he says about what they do,

107
00:09:04,710 --> 00:09:06,180
it's all true.

108
00:09:06,210 --> 00:09:09,880
It's exactly what the survivors of their raids report.

109
00:09:09,940 --> 00:09:14,770
Yes,imagine the stories wildlings tell about us.

110
00:09:16,310 --> 00:09:19,230
Love is the death of duty.

111
00:09:20,480 --> 00:09:22,980
I told that to your friend Jon Snow once.

112
00:09:23,030 --> 00:09:27,230
He didn't listen and neither did you.

113
00:09:27,290 --> 00:09:31,240
Which is why you've abandoned your watch atop the Wall

114
00:09:31,290 --> 00:09:35,240
to come here and read about the terrible things

115
00:09:35,240 --> 00:09:39,410
that may have happened to the girl you love.

116
00:09:39,420 --> 00:09:42,420
I don't love her.

117
00:09:42,470 --> 00:09:44,420
- Yes,you do. - No.

118
00:09:44,420 --> 00:09:46,140
Yes,you do.

119
00:09:46,170 --> 00:09:50,340
Heard it in your voice when you first brought her to me.

120
00:09:50,390 --> 00:09:52,590
I remember how it sounds.

121
00:09:52,640 --> 00:09:54,600
I was in love once.

122
00:09:54,650 --> 00:09:55,930
You were?

123
00:09:55,930 --> 00:10:00,270
You can imagine all manner of horrors

124
00:10:00,270 --> 00:10:02,940
befalling that poor girl and her child.

125
00:10:02,990 --> 00:10:05,740
Is it so difficult to imagine

126
00:10:05,770 --> 00:10:09,860
that an old person was once, more or less,like you?

127
00:10:09,910 --> 00:10:12,530
I'm sorry,Maester.

128
00:10:12,580 --> 00:10:14,280
I didn't mean it like that.

129
00:10:14,330 --> 00:10:18,220
Do you know who I was before I came here?

130
00:10:18,250 --> 00:10:22,290
What I could have been if I'd only said the word?

131
00:10:23,790 --> 00:10:25,630
Of course you do.

132
00:10:25,660 --> 00:10:29,380
I met many girls when I was Aemon Targaryen.

133
00:10:29,430 --> 00:10:33,300
A future king always does.

134
00:10:34,300 --> 00:10:39,640
Some of them were quite forward in their attempts to win my affections.

135
00:10:40,810 --> 00:10:43,110
One of them succeeded.

136
00:10:44,110 --> 00:10:45,730
I was very young.

137
00:10:46,860 --> 00:10:48,680
Who was she?

138
00:10:50,650 --> 00:10:53,240
I could tell you everything about her.

139
00:10:53,290 --> 00:10:55,160
Who she was,

140
00:10:55,190 --> 00:10:56,960
how we met,

141
00:10:56,990 --> 00:10:59,130
the color of her eyes,

142
00:10:59,160 --> 00:11:01,900
and the shape of her nose.

143
00:11:03,800 --> 00:11:05,970
I can see her

144
00:11:06,000 --> 00:11:08,840
right in front of me.

145
00:11:10,690 --> 00:11:14,260
She's more real than you are.

146
00:11:17,350 --> 00:11:21,680
We could spend all night trading tales of lost loves.

147
00:11:21,730 --> 00:11:24,520
Nothing makes the past a sweeter place to visit

148
00:11:24,570 --> 00:11:27,720
than the prospect of imminent death.

149
00:11:27,760 --> 00:11:30,070
Go to bed,Tarly.

150
00:11:36,080 --> 00:11:38,670
Sorry,I can't open the gate for anybody. Orders.

151
00:11:38,700 --> 00:11:40,950
You don't understand. They killed everyone.

152
00:11:41,000 --> 00:11:43,040
Everyone but me and my baby.

153
00:11:43,090 --> 00:11:45,460
They're out there. I saw them on my way here.

154
00:11:45,510 --> 00:11:47,750
<i>They may have seen me. They may have followed me. Please.</i>

155
00:11:47,760 --> 00:11:49,180
<i>I'm sorry,I can't.</i>

156
00:11:49,210 --> 00:11:50,540
<i> If they find us out here,you don't know...</i>

157
00:11:50,600 --> 00:11:52,380
Pyp! Open the gate.

158
00:11:52,430 --> 00:11:55,130
- I can't. - Sam,is that you?

159
00:11:55,180 --> 00:11:56,000
Yes.

160
00:11:57,350 --> 00:11:59,390
Thorne gave me strict orders to not open the gate.

161
00:11:59,390 --> 00:12:02,020
Oh,Pyp,open the fucking gate!

162
00:12:03,480 --> 00:12:05,060
I never heard you curse before.

163
00:12:05,110 --> 00:12:07,190
Yes,well,best get used to it.

164
00:12:13,240 --> 00:12:15,120
Are you all right?

165
00:12:17,070 --> 00:12:19,660
Shh,you're all right.

166
00:12:19,710 --> 00:12:23,580
Of course you are, my brave little fella.

167
00:12:23,630 --> 00:12:26,300
- It was horrible. - I'm so,so sorry.

168
00:12:26,330 --> 00:12:28,130
I didn't know until I got back.

169
00:12:28,170 --> 00:12:29,630
Don't let them send me away,Sam.

170
00:12:29,670 --> 00:12:31,550
- Never. - I know there's no women allowed.

171
00:12:31,590 --> 00:12:35,060
Anyone who tries to throw you out will be having words with me.

172
00:12:35,090 --> 00:12:38,090
From now on,wherever you go,

173
00:12:38,090 --> 00:12:40,590
I go,too.

174
00:12:50,690 --> 00:12:52,520
Get ready!

175
00:12:52,570 --> 00:12:54,740
- Man the gate! - Ready yourselves!

176
00:12:54,780 --> 00:12:56,830
<i>Make haste!</i>

177
00:12:56,860 --> 00:12:58,950
-<i> Prepare!</i> -<i> Up on the Wall!</i>

178
00:12:59,000 --> 00:13:00,560
<i>Quickly!</i> <i>Up! Up!</i>

179
00:13:00,580 --> 00:13:03,780
<i>How many?</i> <i>How many are there?</i>

180
00:13:06,120 --> 00:13:07,960
Beyond the trees!

181
00:13:11,990 --> 00:13:13,630
It's time.

182
00:14:01,180 --> 00:14:03,590
Light them up! Light them all!

183
00:14:13,240 --> 00:14:15,020
Move!

184
00:14:17,690 --> 00:14:19,030
Pick up the pace!

185
00:14:19,030 --> 00:14:21,080
Come on,come on.

186
00:14:27,750 --> 00:14:30,340
Here we go,boys,there's one.

187
00:14:30,370 --> 00:14:33,540
Let's go. There's two.

188
00:14:36,430 --> 00:14:38,130
Let's get the next load.

189
00:14:41,550 --> 00:14:44,000
That's the last of the oil,Ser Alliser.

190
00:14:45,390 --> 00:14:47,090
100,000 you say?

191
00:14:48,220 --> 00:14:49,390
Yes,Ser.

192
00:14:50,390 --> 00:14:52,730
You can say it if you like.

193
00:14:52,730 --> 00:14:56,610
We should have sealed the tunnel while we had the chance,

194
00:14:56,650 --> 00:14:58,130
like you suggested.

195
00:15:00,070 --> 00:15:03,190
It was a difficult decision either way,Ser.

196
00:15:05,460 --> 00:15:08,380
Do you know what leadership means,Lord Snow?

197
00:15:09,130 --> 00:15:12,210
It means that the person in charge gets second-guessed

198
00:15:12,250 --> 00:15:14,830
by every clever little twat with a mouth.

199
00:15:14,880 --> 00:15:17,250
But if he starts second-guessing himself,

200
00:15:17,300 --> 00:15:18,890
that's the end--

201
00:15:19,140 --> 00:15:22,590
for him,for the clever little twats,

202
00:15:22,590 --> 00:15:24,310
for everyone.

203
00:15:24,340 --> 00:15:27,310
This is not the end. Not for us.

204
00:15:27,350 --> 00:15:29,480
Not if you lot do your duty

205
00:15:29,510 --> 00:15:32,070
for however long it takes to beat them back.

206
00:15:33,520 --> 00:15:36,770
And then you get to go on hating me

207
00:15:36,770 --> 00:15:38,440
and I get to go on wishing

208
00:15:38,440 --> 00:15:40,940
your wildling whore had finished the job.

209
00:16:04,130 --> 00:16:05,770
<i>You'll be safe down here.</i>

210
00:16:05,800 --> 00:16:07,680
I'll check on you as soon as I can.

211
00:16:07,720 --> 00:16:10,640
You're leaving me again?

212
00:16:11,720 --> 00:16:13,360
I'm not leaving you.

213
00:16:13,390 --> 00:16:16,140
You're going up there and we're staying down here. That's leaving.

214
00:16:16,190 --> 00:16:18,560
You said from now on we'd stay together.

215
00:16:18,610 --> 00:16:21,620
I didn't mean in the same room.

216
00:16:21,650 --> 00:16:22,980
What are you going to do out there?

217
00:16:22,990 --> 00:16:24,470
- Help my brothers. - How?

218
00:16:25,820 --> 00:16:28,040
You're going to fight the free folk when they come?

219
00:16:28,070 --> 00:16:30,910
They'll kill you. In Mole's Town,they killed everyone.

220
00:16:30,960 --> 00:16:34,550
I can't just hide here with you while they're fighting out there.

221
00:16:34,580 --> 00:16:37,410
Why not? You won't matter up there.

222
00:16:37,470 --> 00:16:39,080
You will down here.

223
00:16:40,340 --> 00:16:43,340
I am a man of the Night's Watch,Gilly.

224
00:16:43,390 --> 00:16:47,510
I made a promise to defend the Wall and I have to keep it

225
00:16:47,560 --> 00:16:50,140
because that's what men do.

226
00:17:02,320 --> 00:17:05,030
Promise me you won't die.

227
00:17:07,660 --> 00:17:11,200
I promise you I won't die.

228
00:17:45,120 --> 00:17:48,400
There's a lot more wildlings on the other side of the Wall than this side.

229
00:17:48,450 --> 00:17:51,370
We've got loads of weapons and things.

230
00:17:51,570 --> 00:17:53,490
It's the perfect place for us to be.

231
00:17:53,540 --> 00:17:55,740
I've never thrown a spear before.

232
00:17:55,740 --> 00:17:58,630
I've never held a sword with a proper edge.

233
00:17:58,660 --> 00:18:01,330
This is no place for me to be.

234
00:18:03,250 --> 00:18:04,720
You're not afraid?

235
00:18:04,750 --> 00:18:07,220
Of course I'm afraid.

236
00:18:07,260 --> 00:18:09,760
There's a band of wildlings coming to kill us.

237
00:18:09,760 --> 00:18:11,230
If you're afraid of a band of wildlings,

238
00:18:11,260 --> 00:18:13,710
how in seven hells did you manage to kill a white walker?

239
00:18:19,980 --> 00:18:22,650
I didn't know I was going to kill it.

240
00:18:22,690 --> 00:18:25,440
But I had to do something. I didn't have any choice.

241
00:18:25,440 --> 00:18:27,440
It was going to kill Gilly and take the baby.

242
00:18:29,440 --> 00:18:32,750
If someone had asked me my name right then,

243
00:18:32,780 --> 00:18:34,450
I wouldn't have known.

244
00:18:36,200 --> 00:18:39,170
I wasn't Samwell Tarly anymore.

245
00:18:39,200 --> 00:18:41,960
I wasn't a steward in the Night's Watch

246
00:18:41,960 --> 00:18:44,710
or son of Randyll Tarly or any of that.

247
00:18:45,960 --> 00:18:48,050
I was nothing at all.

248
00:18:49,930 --> 00:18:51,880
And when you're nothing at all,

249
00:18:51,930 --> 00:18:54,550
there's no more reason to be afraid.

250
00:18:56,350 --> 00:18:58,360
But you're afraid now?

251
00:18:59,220 --> 00:19:00,860
Yes,well...

252
00:19:02,730 --> 00:19:04,810
I'm not nothing anymore.

253
00:19:24,080 --> 00:19:25,500
Most of their men are up top.

254
00:19:25,500 --> 00:19:28,840
Didn't count more than 20 down here. Leftovers.

255
00:19:28,890 --> 00:19:30,970
They got a big fat one and a little bony one manning the front.

256
00:19:31,010 --> 00:19:32,510
How high are the walls?

257
00:19:32,510 --> 00:19:34,700
Well,we'll be up and over before they know what's happened.

258
00:19:36,510 --> 00:19:39,260
Let's kill some crows!

259
00:19:41,270 --> 00:19:43,650
Come on!

260
00:20:00,200 --> 00:20:02,790
Come on,brothers!

261
00:21:17,690 --> 00:21:19,580
Archers nock.

262
00:21:19,610 --> 00:21:21,780
Everyone else hold.

263
00:21:21,830 --> 00:21:24,280
Grenn,no!

264
00:21:27,200 --> 00:21:30,120
I said nock and hold,you cunts!

265
00:21:30,170 --> 00:21:33,210
- Does nock mean draw? - No,Ser!

266
00:21:33,260 --> 00:21:36,510
- Does fucking hold mean fucking drop? - No,Ser!

267
00:21:36,540 --> 00:21:39,760
- You all plan to die here tonight? - No,Ser!

268
00:21:39,800 --> 00:21:42,260
That's very good to hear. Draw!

269
00:21:46,520 --> 00:21:48,550
No,down below!

270
00:21:58,230 --> 00:22:00,700
Draw! Light them up.

271
00:22:15,160 --> 00:22:17,830
Come on,get up!

272
00:22:17,880 --> 00:22:19,720
They're attacking the southern gate!

273
00:22:19,750 --> 00:22:21,890
<i>- Now?</i> - Now.

274
00:22:25,220 --> 00:22:28,980
I'm going down there. Brother Slynt,you have the Wall.

275
00:22:29,010 --> 00:22:29,710
What?

276
00:22:31,560 --> 00:22:34,770
What are you fucking waiting for? Loose!

277
00:22:34,820 --> 00:22:38,170
You heard the man. Loose!

278
00:23:15,440 --> 00:23:16,980
You,over there.

279
00:23:21,900 --> 00:23:22,930
- Did you get one? - No.

280
00:23:25,540 --> 00:23:27,700
Ah,shit,Pyp! Shit.

281
00:23:27,740 --> 00:23:29,370
- Sam. - Yeah?

282
00:23:29,410 --> 00:23:31,010
I think we're gonna die.

283
00:23:31,240 --> 00:23:33,240
If you keep missing,we will.

284
00:23:43,090 --> 00:23:44,420
Come on! Come on!

285
00:23:49,890 --> 00:23:50,590
Brothers!

286
00:23:51,600 --> 00:23:55,180
100 generations have defended this castle.

287
00:23:55,230 --> 00:23:57,980
She's never fallen before.

288
00:23:58,020 --> 00:23:59,430
She will not fall tonight.

289
00:23:59,490 --> 00:24:02,000
Those are Thenns at our walls.

290
00:24:02,660 --> 00:24:04,940
They eat the flesh of the men they kill.

291
00:24:04,990 --> 00:24:08,160
Do you want to fill the belly of a Thenn tonight?

292
00:24:08,190 --> 00:24:09,490
No!

293
00:24:09,530 --> 00:24:11,030
Tonight we fight.

294
00:24:11,080 --> 00:24:13,450
And when the sun rises, I promise you,

295
00:24:13,500 --> 00:24:15,420
Castle Black will stand!

296
00:24:16,540 --> 00:24:18,750
The Night's Watch will stand.

297
00:24:22,120 --> 00:24:25,590
With me now! Now with me!

298
00:25:21,650 --> 00:25:24,270
No discipline. No training.

299
00:25:24,320 --> 00:25:27,110
Gang of thieves, that's all this is.

300
00:25:27,160 --> 00:25:29,660
I commanded the City Watch of King's Landing.

301
00:25:29,780 --> 00:25:31,350
Those men obeyed orders.

302
00:25:31,470 --> 00:25:33,540
We can't just let them attack the gate!

303
00:25:33,660 --> 00:25:37,000
The bars of those gates are four inches of cold-rolled steel.

304
00:25:37,000 --> 00:25:39,500
Those are giants riding mammoths down there!

305
00:25:39,500 --> 00:25:42,000
Do you think your cold-rolled steel is gonna stop them?

306
00:25:42,010 --> 00:25:43,010
No such thing as giants.

307
00:25:43,340 --> 00:25:46,010
A story for the children.

308
00:25:47,930 --> 00:25:48,810
Brother Slynt.

309
00:25:49,850 --> 00:25:52,000
We just got word that Ser Alliser needs you below.

310
00:25:54,520 --> 00:25:57,320
You're the most experienced man he's got,Ser,and he needs you.

311
00:25:58,610 --> 00:25:59,660
Needed below?

312
00:26:00,410 --> 00:26:02,380
Yes. Yes.

313
00:26:11,750 --> 00:26:15,250
Archers,nock your arrows!

314
00:26:15,290 --> 00:26:17,790
Nock arrows!

315
00:26:17,840 --> 00:26:19,540
Draw!

316
00:26:21,010 --> 00:26:23,180
Loose!

317
00:26:37,060 --> 00:26:40,310
- They won't summit before dawn. - how do you know that

318
00:26:40,360 --> 00:26:42,400
Because I've made that climb.

319
00:26:42,450 --> 00:26:45,070
I think they're in a bigger hurry than you were.

320
00:26:48,290 --> 00:26:50,150
Hold the bridge!</i>

321
00:26:50,210 --> 00:26:52,320
Hold,wait for it!</i>

322
00:26:52,370 --> 00:26:55,210
Come on with the rocks!</i>

323
00:27:00,830 --> 00:27:02,300
Nock!

324
00:27:04,220 --> 00:27:05,670
Draw!

325
00:27:09,340 --> 00:27:10,640
Loose!

326
00:27:29,610 --> 00:27:31,610
Down!

327
00:28:05,730 --> 00:28:07,230
No! No!

328
00:28:27,250 --> 00:28:28,840
To the gate. Come on,let's move.

329
00:28:32,890 --> 00:28:34,170
It's gonna open.

330
00:29:38,990 --> 00:29:41,360
I got one right through the heart. He's dead.

331
00:29:41,410 --> 00:29:43,780
- Oh,is it over? - No.

332
00:29:43,830 --> 00:29:44,700
Well,then...

333
00:29:53,200 --> 00:29:56,290
You're all right. You're all right.

334
00:29:58,590 --> 00:30:00,760
I'll get help.

335
00:30:02,550 --> 00:30:04,850
Maester Aemon is coming.

336
00:30:04,880 --> 00:30:06,800
He's gonna make it all right.

337
00:30:18,310 --> 00:30:20,550
- Now. - Now!

338
00:31:53,970 --> 00:31:55,730
The outer gate won't hold.

339
00:31:55,730 --> 00:31:58,700
Take five men, hold the inner gate.

340
00:31:58,700 --> 00:31:59,610
Aye.

341
00:32:02,620 --> 00:32:04,050
Hold the gate.

342
00:32:04,490 --> 00:32:06,690
If they make it through...

343
00:32:09,070 --> 00:32:10,560
They won't.

344
00:32:12,990 --> 00:32:15,660
Come on,Hill. And you,Cooper.

345
00:32:15,710 --> 00:32:17,800
You three,on me.

346
00:32:18,920 --> 00:32:20,700
Come on,you lazy bastards.

347
00:32:25,090 --> 00:32:26,090
Oil.

348
00:32:28,090 --> 00:32:30,230
Oil on the ramp!

349
00:32:39,350 --> 00:32:40,600
Protect the gate!

350
00:33:14,640 --> 00:33:16,520
Get him inside.

351
00:33:20,640 --> 00:33:22,730
Hold the fucking gate!

352
00:33:22,780 --> 00:33:24,000
Hold it!

353
00:34:23,370 --> 00:34:24,870
We need more men down here.

354
00:34:24,930 --> 00:34:27,430
- We have to hold the gate. - But we need men here.

355
00:34:27,460 --> 00:34:29,710
Tell Jon. He's in command.

356
00:34:29,760 --> 00:34:30,780
Let's go.

357
00:34:39,810 --> 00:34:42,980
Get me to the top! You hear me?!

358
00:34:47,480 --> 00:34:49,900
Your name's Olly,right?

359
00:34:49,900 --> 00:34:53,150
Listen to me,Olly. Get me to the top.

360
00:34:53,200 --> 00:34:56,380
And when we give the signal, bring us back down.

361
00:34:57,370 --> 00:34:58,960
You hear me?

362
00:35:03,550 --> 00:35:06,220
Find a weapon,Olly. Fight them.

363
00:35:39,000 --> 00:35:41,150
Clear the way! Let's go!

364
00:35:41,190 --> 00:35:43,290
- Out of the way! - Get out of here!

365
00:36:00,720 --> 00:36:01,940
Cut the rope!

366
00:36:09,310 --> 00:36:10,310
Wait! No!

367
00:36:25,830 --> 00:36:27,880
- We need more archers. - Here I am.

368
00:36:27,920 --> 00:36:30,250
- Come on.</i> - Quickly.</i>

369
00:36:32,470 --> 00:36:34,390
What are you doing up here?

370
00:36:34,420 --> 00:36:36,920
The wildlings are over the walls.

371
00:36:36,970 --> 00:36:38,760
Ser Alliser's fallen.

372
00:36:38,810 --> 00:36:41,480
The castle won't stand much longer.

373
00:36:43,180 --> 00:36:46,150
Edd,you have the Wall.

374
00:36:48,400 --> 00:36:50,850
If they try the mammoths again,drop fire on them.

375
00:36:50,900 --> 00:36:53,690
If the climbers get too high, drop the scythe on them.

376
00:36:59,200 --> 00:37:01,670
Come,brothers. Now fight with me!

377
00:37:02,420 --> 00:37:05,600
Might as well enjoy our last night,right,boys?

378
00:37:06,340 --> 00:37:08,250
Light the fuckers up!

379
00:37:08,290 --> 00:37:11,460
Nock! Draw!</i>

380
00:37:12,380 --> 00:37:14,630
Loose!

381
00:37:23,220 --> 00:37:24,390
How are we gonna stop that?

382
00:37:24,390 --> 00:37:25,720
Shot 20 arrows in him already.

383
00:37:25,720 --> 00:37:27,190
You heard Jon. We hold the gate.

384
00:37:27,220 --> 00:37:28,640
Jon Snow's not Lord Commander.

385
00:37:28,690 --> 00:37:30,000
We hold the gate!

386
00:37:39,240 --> 00:37:41,740
Mother,save me. Father,save me.

387
00:37:41,740 --> 00:37:42,960
The gods aren't down here.

388
00:37:42,990 --> 00:37:44,830
It's the six of us. You hear me?

389
00:37:50,580 --> 00:37:53,250
Night gathers and now my watch begins.

390
00:37:53,300 --> 00:37:55,720
It shall not end until my death.</i>

391
00:37:55,750 --> 00:37:58,220
I shall take no wife, hold no lands,

392
00:37:58,260 --> 00:37:59,840
father no children.</i>

393
00:37:59,890 --> 00:38:02,430
I shall wear no crown and win no glory.

394
00:38:02,430 --> 00:38:04,640
I shall live and die at my post.

395
00:38:04,680 --> 00:38:06,560
I am the sword in the darkness.

396
00:38:06,600 --> 00:38:08,400
I am the watcher on the walls.

397
00:38:08,430 --> 00:38:11,430
I am the shield that guards the realms of men.

398
00:38:11,440 --> 00:38:15,490
I pledge my life and honor to the Night's Watch

399
00:38:15,520 --> 00:38:18,190
for this night and all the nights to come!

400
00:38:23,950 --> 00:38:25,410
I don't want you out there.

401
00:38:25,450 --> 00:38:27,670
You can't protect me forever.

402
00:38:27,700 --> 00:38:30,090
There won't be anywhere to hide if the castle falls.

403
00:38:33,120 --> 00:38:35,680
I need him more than I need you.

404
00:39:49,170 --> 00:39:50,400
We need you,boy.

405
00:42:10,590 --> 00:42:12,040
Jon Snow.

406
00:42:12,180 --> 00:42:15,430
Hush. Don't talk.

407
00:42:19,520 --> 00:42:21,520
Do you remember the cave?

408
00:42:26,440 --> 00:42:29,240
We should have bstayed in the cave.

409
00:42:33,200 --> 00:42:35,200
We'll go back there.

410
00:42:41,290 --> 00:42:44,620
You know nothing,Jon Snow.

411
00:43:19,880 --> 00:43:22,290
Drop the scythe,boys!

412
00:43:44,430 --> 00:43:46,940
- Hoist her up. -  Hoist her up!

413
00:43:52,860 --> 00:43:54,940
They've had enough for one night.

414
00:43:59,120 --> 00:44:01,350
Don't cheer too loud.

415
00:44:02,840 --> 00:44:05,870
They still outnumber us 1,000 to one.

416
00:44:14,180 --> 00:44:15,030
Tormund.

417
00:44:15,970 --> 00:44:17,320
It's over.

418
00:44:18,550 --> 00:44:19,890
Let it end.

419
00:44:19,940 --> 00:44:22,220
This is how a man ends.

420
00:44:30,200 --> 00:44:31,730
Put him in chains.

421
00:44:32,820 --> 00:44:34,350
We'll question him later.

422
00:44:37,370 --> 00:44:42,030
I should have thrown you from the top of the Wall,boy!

423
00:44:42,830 --> 00:44:43,880
Aye.

424
00:44:44,910 --> 00:44:46,560
You should have.

425
00:44:54,090 --> 00:44:56,560
Whoa,it's me. It's me.

426
00:45:00,590 --> 00:45:02,430
I promised you,didn't I?

427
00:45:17,410 --> 00:45:18,510
We held them off.

428
00:45:19,160 --> 00:45:21,000
For one night.

429
00:45:21,160 --> 00:45:23,500
This is a great victory.

430
00:45:23,530 --> 00:45:25,200
A great victory?

431
00:45:27,250 --> 00:45:29,510
Mance was testing our defenses.

432
00:45:29,540 --> 00:45:31,120
He almost made it through.

433
00:45:31,170 --> 00:45:33,960
And he has more giants. He has more mammoths.

434
00:45:34,010 --> 00:45:36,410
He has 1,000 times as many men.

435
00:45:40,050 --> 00:45:42,240
They'll hit us again tonight.

436
00:45:42,690 --> 00:45:45,100
Maybe we can hold them off for a day or two,

437
00:45:45,140 --> 00:45:46,380
but we'll never beat them.

438
00:45:48,110 --> 00:45:49,080
Where are we going?

439
00:45:49,530 --> 00:45:51,190
Going to find Mance.

440
00:45:51,230 --> 00:45:53,930
To fi--- you can't do that.

441
00:45:53,960 --> 00:45:55,810
No one gave you any orders.

442
00:45:57,570 --> 00:45:58,850
Who's left to give orders?

443
00:45:59,990 --> 00:46:02,740
The wildling army's only an army because of Mance.

444
00:46:02,740 --> 00:46:05,490
He united 100 warring tribes.

445
00:46:05,540 --> 00:46:07,580
Without Mance, they lose their leader.

446
00:46:07,580 --> 00:46:10,300
They lose their purpose. They go back to fighting each other.

447
00:46:10,330 --> 00:46:12,030
Scatter back to their homes.

448
00:46:12,170 --> 00:46:14,330
Without Mance?

449
00:46:14,380 --> 00:46:15,800
You're going to kill him?

450
00:46:15,840 --> 00:46:17,140
I'm gonna try.

451
00:46:17,170 --> 00:46:19,000
They'll never let you within 100 yards of him.

452
00:46:19,060 --> 00:46:21,260
And even if they did,even if you managed to kill him--

453
00:46:21,260 --> 00:46:23,840
They'll kill me? If I don't go,they'll kill me anyway.

454
00:46:23,890 --> 00:46:25,310
They'll kill the rest of us,too.

455
00:46:25,350 --> 00:46:27,900
They won't just kill you.</i>

456
00:46:27,930 --> 00:46:29,770
They'll boil you. They'll flay you.

457
00:46:29,820 --> 00:46:31,320
They'll make it last days.

458
00:46:34,100 --> 00:46:37,660
You're right. It's a bad plan.

459
00:46:39,660 --> 00:46:41,090
What's your plan?

460
00:47:24,990 --> 00:47:26,260
They held the gate.

461
00:47:36,380 --> 00:47:38,770
Get some brothers down here to help you.

462
00:47:41,090 --> 00:47:43,390
We need to burn the bodies.

463
00:48:04,190 --> 00:48:06,100
Raise the outer gate.

464
00:48:07,250 --> 00:48:09,080
Then lower it again as soon as I'm out.

465
00:48:21,210 --> 00:48:22,510
What are you doing?

466
00:48:22,710 --> 00:48:24,630
I promised Mormont I'd never lose it again.

467
00:48:29,770 --> 00:48:30,940
In case I don't come back.

468
00:48:39,730 --> 00:48:40,680
Jon.

469
00:48:46,450 --> 00:48:47,440
Come back.

470
00:49:00,320 --> 00:49:03,030
<font color=#70DBDB>=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=http://ytet.org=-   proudly presents </font>

471
00:49:03,120 --> 00:49:06,730
<font color=#70DBDB>-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- 时间轴调校:紫月

472
00:49:06,820 --> 00:49:09,730
<font color=#70DBDB>Game of thrones season04 ep09</font>



